Hello, teachers and students, good evening, I am Tao Hui from the College of Fashion at Wuhan Fanzhi University.
Thank you very much to CLO Shanghai for providing such a very good academic exchange today and the exchange platform for talent training.
What I want to share with you today is that digital technology and fashion can continue to develop.
As the host just said, digital technology has become an important engine in today's era.
In the process of sustainable development, digital technology and sustainable development are inseparable.
So when we share the topic of digital technology and sustainable development with you today,
I would like to first discuss with you about what is sustainable fashion and development.
Let me show you a process chart.
Let us understand the concept of sustainable fashion.
What is sustainable fashion and development?
In 1962, the American artist Rachel Carson published her recent book,
The Spring, which was about the first sound of human environmental protection.
In our modern language, it is called the sound of young people.
Then in 1971, after her focus on the real world design was published by Victor Pavanak,
some sustainable design movements also appeared.
In 1991, the foreign brands Papagramia and Esprit
held their first fashion exhibition.
And this is the first ever annual event.
So this year's fashion 2020 is a turning point.
The fashion industry began to pay attention to sustainability.
In 2009, the so-called D'Avers Forum in the fashion industry
led by Copenhagen's Sustainable Fashion Highline Forum
actually started to really open the fashion industry for sustainable development.
In 2019, the United States and Europe established the Sustainable Fashion Alliance
to deal with the environmental crisis of fast fashion.
From our simple introduction just now,
it has been half a century since 1962.
Modern people have been working hard to protect the environment.
Let's take a look.
With this sustainable fashion promotion,
many of these effective measures have come true.
Let me give you an example.
At present, the current status of the global fashion industry,
you may also know more about it.
Due to the influence of trans-fashion,
the consumption of fashion has increased,
and there are such predictions of institutions.
In 2050, the total sales of clothing will reach 1.6 billion,
which is more than three times what we have now.
At the same time, the production method of the textile industry
has also caused the waste of the fashion industry,
or the environmental pollution of the aircraft,
which is a more serious factor.
So what I just said is that
for the current status of the fashion industry,
some very effective measures have come true.
First of all, we see that in 2018,
in New York,
the fashion week was established.
First of all, I would like to emphasize that
all products, all works,
must be organic or renewable.
Based on such a threshold and要素,
all products that participate in the fashion week
must be sustainable.
At the same time,
now, about sustainable forums,
or such institutions,
such meetings,
they are also endless.
We have put this sustainable fashion as our focus.
It is worth mentioning that
in 2021,
during the fourth World Exports Forum,
the International Exports Forum of China
established the International Exports Forum of China
for Sustainable Fashion and Lifestyle Professional Cooperation.
So sometimes we can see
that our Chinese fashion industry
has already put the sustainable fashion lifestyle
at the highest level of our current life.
So what we can see is
some very effective measures and policies
for sustainable development of fashion.
There are also some activities.
At the same time,
we can also take a look at
and understand that
after many years of development,
what is the trend of sustainable fashion
at present?
Let's take a look at it now.
There are mainly six representatives.
The first one is from the cross-border to the non-border.
For example,
we all know that
the fashion of fashion,
or the fashion of sports,
or the high-level,
are in such a floating state.
At the same time,
the fusion of fashion and high-end
from the two-border to the non-border,
and the high-level for a year,
the original two-border,
and the four-border,
now to the non-border.
This kind of promotion,
the fusion of marketing and social,
has also become the first point
that we want to mention,
from the cross-border to the non-border.
Then the second one
is that design plays
a more and more important role.
In the past,
designers,
the focus was on
how to make the product sellable,
and provide more beautiful feelings.
So now the designers
may have changed their roles more.
And in the sustainable development of fashion,
designers should become
a pioneer.
The second one
is to be a transmitter,
an educator,
and a promoter.
Including,
now we see
Nike,
Burberry,
their current CEO
actually has the background of a designer.
So,
the future of this world
is more about
the business of design.
Then the third point
is high-tech,
to penetrate
our clothing industry.
Everyone knows now,
from our early digital printing,
to laser cutting,
and including
the 3D printing of
Dianfu World.
Of course,
3D printing
is expected
in the future.
But it is impossible
to completely replace the design.
So here,
we also said that
this design is still very important.
The fourth feature
is this trend.
That is to say,
sustainable fast fashion
will become the mainstream.
Then we also know
that many fast fashion brands
are a
low price
and high sales.
Then its rapid response
led consumers
to buy quickly
and quickly abandon it.
So it caused
a rapid rise in waste.
So now we emphasize
sustainable fast fashion.
Just like that,
I added a little bit.
In the past,
more and more attention
is focused on
commercial interests,
cost-efficiency,
and low-cost.
So a low-cost
product like this
must be,
from a certain point of view,
sustainable.
We are responsible
for it.
So now,
it is called
sustainable fast fashion.
We know that
when it comes to sustainability,
it involves the environment
and the protection of workers,
as well as the welfare of the public,
as well as the environment,
logistics,
and so on,
including some problems
with production lines.
So now,
we have established
a fast supply chain platform,
which provides design,
see-through,
board,
design,
and production.
For example,
the legendary manufacturing,
as well as the designers,
factory,
and face materials,
all together,
such a medium-sized platform,
such as assembly,
manufacturing,
and so on.
So now,
we also see
more and more fast fashion
starting to develop
in a high-end way.
That is to say,
they pay more attention to quality,
and pay more attention to
the demand
for the most quality
for consumers.
At the same time,
the sustainable aspect
is changing.
In the past,
we have seen
and heard about
this kind of
competition between
entrepreneurs.
In the past,
we have seen
and heard about
this kind of
competition between
entrepreneurs.
As long as we now
prove through time
that they are
a cooperative relationship,
it is a pure
relationship.
Online search,
online experience,
through online
virtual digital technology,
virtual,
that is,
mature experience,
and then to the offline
to feel.
Then the sixth point
is the transparency
of the industrial chain.
There is a tracking code.
Then we can use
this tracking code
to understand
the production process
of this product
and the production process
of micro-products.
Is it sustainable?
What we simply
introduce is
the trend of sustainable
fashion development.
Then we focus on
the sustainable development
of the fashion industry chain.
Then I summed it up.
Then we can
look at it from
five aspects.
The first is
the development of materials.
The second is
the production of production.
The third is
sales and sales.
Then the fourth
is recycling.
In fact,
this is the stage
when life
is about to end.
Then how to use it again?
Then I put the design responsibility
at the end.
Then the design
just said that
the designer
in sustainable fashion
is responsible for
this responsibility.
So later
I will also give everyone
a related sharing.
Then we see
the four pieces in front of this.
In fact,
in each section,
we are doing
sustainable fashion.
In this process,
we can infiltrate
and can do
something
in the process.
Because in the past
many people may think
that sustainable is
an environmental meeting.
One is recycling
and the other is reuse.
But in fact,
in every section
of the fashion industry,
all the sustainable
people are integrated
into it.
Then let's take a look at it first.
For example,
maybe
the 2016 Spring and Summer
press conference
of Hanwayang
showed this water-soluble
fashion
and emphasized its
solubility.
So this is also
the designer
investigating
how to use
such a material
to reduce it faster.
Then we also see
that many designers
are also
or including themselves
are constantly
exploring
and understanding
how to develop
more
such a raw material
with biological
regenerative behavior
for fashion design
and industry.
At the same time,
in the segment of marketing,
we also see
that London's
sustainable entrepreneur
Tara Poppins
she
created this
Body Ones
such a shopping network.
In fact,
it emphasizes the accuracy
of purchase.
Effective purchase
should not be repeated
or ineffective purchase
So this is
one of her intentions.
In addition,
an American brand
Avalance
emphasizes
transparent marketing.
In each section
For example,
take a belt as an example
So from the beginning
of the belt
this raw material
to its buckle
sewing
to the shipping section
What is its cost?
It will be in
its product
clearly marked
so that
consumers
are more clear
about
where my money
is used
and also
reduce the cost
as much as possible
It is not necessary
to make such a purchase
with its design
The biggest feature
is the simplification
So if you are interested
you can take a look at it
Then the other is
the post-sale section
If this is H&M
with our
National Fashion University
Fashion Academy
The recovery plan
of the activity
to put on these jeans
Because we
actually did a survey
Everyone
is a certain age
at least
his clothes
There are seven or eight
such jeans
And this is
relatively fast
Although the life of the jeans
is very long
But in fact
it is in the process of changing
So
with our National Fashion University
joint activities
such an activity
Including
Upholstered
牛仔
Upgraded
Let it
become an art
What we see now
is that
in 2014
The World Fashion Conference
held in our school
This gift to the guests
is
Upholstered
This art
Eight main guests
From the simple introduction just now
We have learned
the life cycle of a dress
From the acquisition of the entire raw material
to the consumer
to the end of the weapon
In fact, we
really have a lot of things to do
But we have already talked about
the first few aspects
But in fact
In this
We will find
that these
may already be familiar to everyone
So in this industry
For everyone
In the familiar sustainable development path
We also felt
Digital technology
Obviously it has become
our sustainable development
A new growth point
Then let's
Let's take a look at
digital technology
How to assist our
Fashion sustainable development
So this one
I gave this case
Everyone is very familiar
This is
The new design of the Netherlands
The designer
Irish Van Hobben
Then his
In the press conference in 2019
3D printing technology
In fact, we know
Early
3D printing technology
When presented
It is also a revolutionary
It can be said that it is a subversive
Then it is mainly used in industrial products
It is a solidified form
But
As the printing technology
Continuous improvement
And then the material
This diversification
We will see
The application of it in clothing
More and more
Then this presentation
Can effectively satisfy
Customer
The need for personalized design
So we are buying clothes
If it can be more accurate
So we will grow to it
Will be deeper
Will not be easily abandoned
So let's take a look from this
3D printing technology
How is it
It can be for our future
For example, it is sustainable
It has such an impact
I believe our online audience
If you see
Such a work
You will also have this kind of
A feeling of excitement
Also hope to be able to
Build for yourself
A suitable
3D printing work
When we talk about
This 3D printing work
In fact, there is one
Very important
Just talked about
The problem of material
If it is the future
If it can present
More organic
Can be reduced
Can be biological
Or like to reuse
Such a product
Such a micro
Then it will definitely
Move to
Our fashion
Can develop
A very effective
A group
Or an engine
Let's take a look
There is a 3D printing company
Called Simplify
The natural material it studies
Printed 3D printing shoes
Then it is a
Very good
In addition to our shoes
Can satisfy
The needs of traditionalists
At the same time
Its material
Such a natural material
Is satisfied
Our most comfortable
A requirement
So the material
Breakthrough
In the future
Used in fashion
In the product
3D printing
Is not far away from us
Especially in the case of
Publicization
It should be
Not far away
Then let's take a look
In the distribution
More influential
Is the app
Is it
It's a digital printer
Made by the post office
Make more customers
Not willing to go out
Or not willing to go to the store
You can go online
To feel
This kind of experience
So with
The virtual printing
It's getting more and more mature
It's that kind of
The sense of experience
Will be stronger
It also makes our consumers
When shopping
Be more accurate
As opposed to when you buy it
We now find that
In fact, a lot of people
Have done research
Online shopping
Purchasing
In that clothing
Is still relatively high
Because everyone feels
It looks
This picture is still better
But wearing it on yourself
It's always a little bit worse
And the technology
3D scanning
Personalization
Brand high-end
This is one of my personal experiences
I went to the store
To experience
In the 3D scanning space
Two minutes
I scanned your body
Out
Give you the most accurate
After such a data
At the same time
Give you a special review
Then give you
A suggestion for your purchase
So in the end
The whole
The data he got
You can
According to this data
You choose
His current style
Or online style
He also has a style in the physical store
You can try it on
After you're done
You can choose
Purchase
Then he will
According to your size
To do
Suitable for your custom
So give it in advance
In this way
Make our shopping
Can be more accurate
Consumers can get
More satisfied
Such a cosmetic product
Share clothes
Is also
A hot topic in recent years
A topic
China's
One or three
Such a brand
A new brand
In 2009
Received
This is a song
With the fashion summit
This invitation
Is also on it
A dialogue
So in fact
We all know
Especially women
In his clothes
Clothes
But can't bear to lose
So this dress
If used to exchange
Then maybe
Can play its value again
At the same time
You can also find
A new one
Clothing experience
So the sharing of clothes
Is also
We recommend
Sustainable development
A very important
Now
We have also done a survey
Many women
Will share with their jackets
Other clothes
May be in doubt
Of course
Our main
This sharing
It should be
In terms of outer dress
Including the United States
For example
It is also a exchange
I don't need it anymore
Right
I put this dress
It's a pity to throw it away
Especially now
The family
Are all babies
Two babies
It is very important
For the kids
A safety
Comfort
After the child wears it
It's a pity to lose it
You can use this exchange
Or
It's a useful person
Through the online platform
So this is also
A girl
One aspect
It is very important
A statement
In the beginning
Talk about
From the mode of using, manufacturing, and dispensing to now, it has become a circular mode of use.
We can feel it when we look at this picture.
In this way, the design of this function is actually the most important.
As I mentioned earlier, this design should be a soul in the sustainable development of the entire fashion.
So let's take a look again.
If it is a sustainable design, what principles should we follow?
First of all, the first one is reuse, that is, reuse.
Considering such a product, it must be as long-lasting as possible.
At the same time, considering its function, it can be used repeatedly.
So this is what we should consider when designing.
The second one is recycle, which is to recycle and reuse.
For example, after our clothing is used up, I may not need it anymore.
At this time, I can reuse the raw material.
For example, after cutting it, it can regain its value,
rather than being thrown away as a useless waste.
The third one is recovery, which is to recycle and design.
When the life of your clothes is cut off,
how can it be effectively returned to the natural world?
This is what we call a reduction point.
The fourth one is what I mentioned before, which is to recreate,
which is to re-create the design.
This kind of re-creating design actually emphasizes that
if our original design can be stored and reused in a digitalized way,
then the digitalized design becomes the main point.
We can also use this case as an example.
This is what Professor Jiang Minghua of the University of Wuhan,
the University of Hong Kong, designed.
It is a very good idea!
The first part of the process is to re-create the design,
but we should also re-create the design in the way,
and then we can re-create the design in the way it is.
As you see, this is exactly the same as the visual design,
for example, the digitalized design is a form of re-creation.
It has a fixed state,
and it can be re-created very precisely and accurately.
That is, it can be re-created in a very simple way.
If you want a visualized design,
like a digitalized design,
then we can re-create it.
Of course, you see,
If we have such clothes, no one will be able to take them off easily.
Let's look at another video.
This video was made by our students.
We train our students.
We train them to have a sense of smartness in social media.
So they made a video like this.
It is a video that is mainly open to the public.
Let's take a look at the clothes.
They are very fashionable.
For example, when I go to work, I wear a formal dress.
Let's take a look at this case.
361 is a well-known sports brand in China.
Since 2015, it has been using 3D clothing software to design.
We can see that this kind of design really shows the effect of the product.
It is very popular.
From the design to the production of clothes.
This is also a very effective and effective way to reduce waste and shorten the process.
At the same time, it will also show the series of designers.
The biggest advantage is that it can be a digitized database.
When we need it, we can transfer the data from the database at any time.
Second design.
So this is also a very important point for us to develop fashion in the future.
Let me introduce you again.
We are from the University of Wuhan.
We have been working on digital technology and sustainable design education these years.
We have been very focused on sustainable development in fashion these years.
And this is one of the characteristics of our education.
In our department, we have a joint education with some schools abroad.
Sustainable development in fashion.
With the University of Manchester in the UK.
And we have been doing this kind of sustainable design project since 2019.
At the same time, we are also promoting international meetings.
In the course of the graduate students, the graduate students also started this course.
It is a sustainable course.
We also held such a world environmental design competition.
The international meeting with Manchester City University.
It is an international meeting about fashion and climate change.
Then we just talked about it.
In our department, we also started such a course.
It is a virtual online course.
Then we also want to let our students be able to master it more comprehensively.
So this is their course homework.
You can also take a look.
There are some products introduced here in the class.
For example, the
The
However, for our students, it is a starting point for them to master the skills.
At the same time, it is also the future development of our industry that provides such a technical talent guarantee.
This is a special design designed by senior students using 3D cloth.
For our graduate students, they also use 3D cloth to create a traditional style of clothing design.
At the same time, we also use 3D cloth technology to use it in the study life.
In particular, this is a very good presentation by 3D cloth.
This is what our graduate students use 3D cloth to create a sustainable clothing design using 3D cloth.
This is a very good presentation by senior students using 3D cloth technology to create a sustainable clothing design using 3D cloth.
The sustainable fashion nature that I just mentioned,
from my personal point of view,
I think it should be on two aspects.
One is the micro level, which is to extend the life cycle of the product.
The second is the condition of the material.
The third is that it can be reduced to the end of life.
It can be reduced and returned to nature.
From the perspective of the red light,
I think the first one is to satisfy people's most beautiful life goals.
The second one is to develop from the traditional culture of the nation.
It should be the development of excellent traditional culture.
So based on this, we also did this experiment.
Then we started the anti-stress virtual imitation experiment course.
Then let the students learn about culture in the experience of traditional clothing culture.
At the same time, I also mastered the technology of virtual imitation.
Use 3D to do digital clothing design.
Of course, this is our cooperation with the Hubei City Hall of the Party.
We made a virtual imitation of Han Junmin and Master Chen Bohua's red-striped flower champagne queen.
You can see that the degree of this imitation is still very good.
So this is for those who want to go on a trip like this.
Or eat a boat.
There are also some products that are not easy to preserve.
After we built a database,
we can make more of them.
One is to preserve.
In addition, you can also learn more online.
This is one of the imitations that everyone can see.
We not only put this picture,
but also include his embroidery.
All made a very good imitation.
At the same time, we are also doing the traditional clothing.
Also doing digital technology.
Do this virtual imitation.
You can see this is your home.
Big red, non-fish patterned women's long shirt.
And this is a modern non-fish patterned women's long shirt.
Recently, you dig a dress and a dress.
This is a cotton dress.
And this is also a traditional clothing database.
The introduction just now,
as well as the sustainable fashion development,
and how digital technology can help the fashion industry.
We can see that the design plays a role in this.
Due to the participation and assistance of digital technology,
we will find that the design will continue to play a role in the entire fashion industry chain.
It will be more prominent in the future.
There is a sentence that I want to share with you.
I just said that our fashion can be sustainable development.
In fact, it is to satisfy the desire of people's best life.
To satisfy people's best life is our struggle goal.
With the arrival of the universe,
digital technology has become an important driver and engine in the development of fashion.
So what I want to say here is that digital design education
and sustainable fashion industry development
is also a time-honored demand for talent.
Look at this video.
This is a work of a Japanese designer.
He published a work in 2021.
Through this video,
we can see the value of a digital software in 3D design.
Including the exchange of fabric.
Including the expression of feeling.
And the basic effect of this material.
All very clear.
This is the same as the product design of the 361 I just mentioned.
A series of products are directly introduced.
Dear audience, friends, teachers and students.
That's all for my sharing today.
Thank you all.
Nearby.
And I would like to thank all of the participants.
Thanks for watching.
See you in the next video.
Bye-bye.
.